Buffalo Federation of Women’s Clubs Records
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Buffalo Federation of Women’s Clubs Records
1907 - 1996
1960 - 1996
18 boxes, 4 slim boxes, 2 volumes (10.25 linear ft.)
Buffalo Federation of Women’s Clubs
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Donated by Elizabeth Shenton, Jean McFarrent, John L. Cobb, Wanda Horbett, Helen Yaeger & Gloria McDonald. 74-113, 79-6.
Series I: Administrative Files, 1909-1996; Subseries A: Minutes, correspondence and monthly reports, 1930-1996; Subseries B: Annual committee reports, 1916-1994. (Reports for 1995 forward are filed with Conventions in Series II Subseries A.); Subseries C: Committee files, 1909-1986; Series II: Events and Programs Files, 1907-1996; Subseries A: Conventions, 1907-1996; Subseries B: Federation Days, 1938-1996; Series III: Publications, 1937-1996; Subseries A: Club Life, 1937-1938; Subseries B: Bulletins, 1944-1996; Series IV: Historical Files, 1924-1996; Subseries A: Constitution, by-laws and logo, undated and 1939-1996; Subseries B: Histories, undated and 1975; Subseries C: Rosters, 1926/27 - 1993/94; Subseries D: Past presidents, 1944-1977; Subseries E: Bequests, 1989; Subseries F: Awards and citations, undated and 1963-1985; Subseries G: Photographs, undated and 1965-1992; Subseries H: Scrapbooks, 1958-1980; Subseries I: Clippings, undated and 1924-1990; Subseries J: Publicity, 1967-1996. (Includes press releases and clippings.); Series V: Honorarians, undated and 1954-1988; Series VI: National, State, and Other Federations, 1941-1984; Subseries A: General (National) Federation, 1941-1984; Subseries B: New York State Federation, 1944-1952; Subseries C: Other Federations, 1942-1944
Transferred to Museum Collections Department: 1 souvenir china plate with photograph of Ruth E. Hill, Taiwan, 1969. (Mrs. Hill was BFWC President, 1976-1978.); 5 delegates’ buttons, BFWC annual convention, n.d.
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
An alliance of women's clubs founded in 1905 as the Buffalo City Federation of Women's Clubs; name changed in 1939. Originally comprising 28 member clubs involved in civic activities "to further citizenship, education and philanthropy," the B.F.W.C. comprised some 71 member clubs by 1985.
Women's Societies and Clubs; audiocassettes; commemorative plaques; awards; original photographs; scrapbooks; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006; Kemp, Jack, 1935-2009; Buffalo Federation of Women's Clubs (N.Y.)
Includes minutes, 1930-1996; committee reports, 1936-1996; convention files, 1907-1996; Federation Days files, 1938-1996; bulletins, 1944-1996; rosters, 1926/27-1993/94; photographs, undated and 1965-1992; scrapbooks, 1958-1980; and clippings, undated and 1924-1990. Also included in series I are materials of the Bicentennial Committee (1976), including a tape cassette of a program, correspondence with Congressman Jack Kemp, and a greeting from President Gerald R. Ford.
- Administrative Files, 1909 - 1996; I
  - Minutes, correspondence and monthly reports, 1930 - 1996; IA
    - 1929-1939 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1938-1942 - Files of President Alice Thomas (Box IA Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1942-1959 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1960-1961 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1961-1962 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1962-1963 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1963-1964 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1964-1965 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1965-1966 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1966-1967 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1967-1968 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1968-1969 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1969-1970 (Box IA Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1970-1971 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1973-1974 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1974-1975 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1975-1976 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1977-1978 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1978-1979 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1979-1980 (Box IA Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1980-1981 (Box IA Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1981-1982 (Box IA Box 3, Folder 1A)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 1B)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 1A Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Annual committee reports, 1916 - 1994; IB
    - 1916-1931 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1938-1952 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 1B Box 1, Box-folder 13)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bicentennial Committee, March, 1976 (Box 1B Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1976-1977 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1977-1978 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1978-1979 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1979-1980 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1980-1981 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Publicity chairman, 1980 - 1981 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1981-1982 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Publicity chairman, 1981 - 1982 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1982-1983 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1983-1984 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Publicity chairman, 1982 - 1983 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1984-1985 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1985-1986 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1986-1987 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1987-1988 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1988-1989 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1989-1990 (Box IB Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1990-1991 (Box IB Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1991-1992 (Box IB Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1992-1993 (Box IB Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1993-1994 (Box IB Box 3, Folder 4)
      (For 1994/95- see Conventions.)
  - Committee files, 1909 - 1986; IC
    - Burn Treatment Center, 1977 - 1978 (Box 1C Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Community Improvement, 1951 - 1981 (Box 1C Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Indian Affairs, 1978 - 1980 (Box 1C Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Scholarship Fund, 1909 - 1986 (Box 1C Box 1, Folder 4)
- Events and Programs Files, 1907 - 1996; II
  - Conventions, 1907 - 1996; IIA
    - Register, 1919 - 1928; volumes (documents by form)
    - 1907-1937 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1938-1949 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1950 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1951-1952 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1953-1954 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1955-1959 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1960-1961 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1962 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1963 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1964 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1965 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1966 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1967 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1968 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1969 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1970 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1971 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1972 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1973 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1974 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1975 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1976 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1977 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1978 (Box IIA Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1979 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1980 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1981 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1982 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1983 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1984 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1985 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1986 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1987 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1988 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1989 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1990 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1991 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1992 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1993 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1994 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1995 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1996 (Box IIA Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Federation Days, 1938 - 1996; IIB
    - 1938 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1939 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1940 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1941 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1950s (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1960-1961 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1962 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1963 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1964 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1965 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1966 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1967 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1968 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1969 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1970 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1971 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1972 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1973 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Publicity, 1972 - 1973 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1974 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1975 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1976 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1977 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1978 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1979 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1980 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1981 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1982 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1983 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1984 (Box IIB Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1985 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1986 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1987 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1988 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1989 (IIB Box 2, 5)
    - 1990 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1991 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1992 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1993 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1994 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1995 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1996 (Box IIB Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Other, 1962 - 1972; IIC
    - Scholarship Teas, 1962 - 1972 (Box IIC Box 1, Folder 1)
- Publications, 1937 - 1996; III
  - Club Life, 1937 - 1938; IIIA
    - 1937-1938 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1944 - 1996; IIIB
    - 1944-1952 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1954-1962 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1963-1965 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1966-1968 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1968-1973 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1974-1977 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1980-1983 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1984-1989 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1990-1996 (Box III A-B Box 1, Folder 10)
- Historical Files, 1924 - 1996; IV
  - Constitution, 1939 - 1996; IVA
    - Logo, undated (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder A1)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 1939 - 1996 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder A2)
  - Histories, 1975; IVB
    - Histories - General, undated (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder B1)
    - Histories - “Through the Years, 1905-1975” (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder B2)
  - Rosters, 1926 - 1994; IVC
    - 1926/27 - 1945/46 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder C1)
    - 1947/48 - 1967/68 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder C2)
    - 1968/69 – 1993/94 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder C3)
  - Past presidents, 1944 - 1977; IVD
    - Past presidents - obituaries and resolutions, 1944 - 1977 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder D1)
  - Bequests, 1989; IVE
    - 1989 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder E1)
  - Awards and citations, 1963 - 1985; IVF
    - 1963-1985 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder 1)
    - NCCJ citation, 1970 - 1971 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Plaques, 1983 (Box IV A-E Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1965 - 1992; IVG
    - Past presidents, 1905 - 1988; 1 volume
    - Federation Day (Box IV G Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Persons - Altman, Sadie Raynor (IV G Box 1, 2)
    - Persons - Horton, Katherine Pratt (Box IV G Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Federation Day, 1965 - 1968 (Box IV G Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Federation Day, 1973 (Box IV G Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Federation Day, 1973 (Box IV G Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Federation Day, 1978 - 1979
    - Convention, 1991 - 1992 (Box IV G Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbooks, 1958 - 1980; IVH
    - March 1958 - March 1960 (Box IV H Box 1)
    - March 1960 - March 1962 (Box IV H Box 1)
    - March 1962 - March 1969 (Box IV H Box 1)
    - 1969 - 1971 (Box IV H Box 1)
    - Gerontology, 1970 - 1971 (Box IV H Box 2)
    - Feb. 1971 - Nov. 1972 (Box IV H Box 2)
    - Jan. - Dec. 1973 (Box IV H Box 2)
    - Jan. 1974 - Mar. 1975 (Box IV H Box 2)
    - Mar. 1975 - Mar. 1976 (Box IV H Box 2)
    - Community Improvement Project (Haven House), 1979 - 1980
  - Clippings, 1924 - 1990; IVI
    - Undated (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1924-1939 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1940-1948 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1955-1959 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1963-1966 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1967-1969 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1970-1971 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1972-1973 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1974-1975 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1976-1977 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1978-1979 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1981-1984 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1986-1990 (Box IV I-J Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Publicity, 1996; IVJ
    - 1967-1988
    - 1988-1990
    - 1992-1994
    - 1994-1996
- Honorarians, 1954 - 1988; V
  - Miscellaneous (Box V Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and reports, 1954 - 1959 (Box V Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and reports, 1960 - 1962 (Box V Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and reports, 1963 - 1964 (Box V Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and reports, 1965 - 1967 (Box V Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and reports, 1968 - 1969 (Box V Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and reports, 1970 - 1972 (Box V Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes and reports, 1973 - 1974 (Box V Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes and reports, 1975 - 1976 (Box V Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes and reports, 1977 - 1978 (Box V Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes and reports, 1980 - 1988 (Box V Box 1, Folder 11)
- National, State, and Other Federations, 1941 - 1984; VI
  - General (National) Federation, 1941 - 1984; VIA
    - 1941-1984 (Box VI A-C Box 1, Folder A1)
  - New York State Federation, 1944 - 1952; VIB
    - 1944-1952 (Box VI A-C Box 1, Folder B1)
  - Other Federations, 1942 - 1944; VIC
    - New York City Federation, 1944 (Box VI A-C Box 1, Folder C1)
    - Western New York Federation, 1942 - 1944 (Box VI A-C Box 1, Folder C2)